

# Resume Of: Md. Ferdous Khan Roman.

# **MAILING ADDRESS**

House - Showpno Bastob,38/B, Road-02, Chandmia Housing, Mohammadpur. Dhaka, Bangladesh. Phone- 01817086095. frk.roman@gmail.com.

### 01. PERSONAL SUMMARY.

I am a self-motivated and will powered individual who is ready to give all my attention and problem-solving skills to get a job done and am a very reliable person who requires little or no supervision in getting task accomplished. I adapt well to changing needs and priorities and can work under pressure if such situations arise. More than 14 years' experience in FM CG retail, Garments, knit, Accessories and solid knowledge on Category Management on Grocery, House hold, General Merchandise, Chemical, Accessories, Construction Material, Yarn, Print Material, Electric equipment, and lots of categories under Garments, Accessories, and retail super market, Also have hands on experience on Forecasting and Inventory Management, **SAP MM/SD Module**.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Supply chain**

- Extensive knowledge of coordinating all of the entities involved in a supply chain.
- Knowledge of managing returns and rejections professionally & promptly with suppliers.
- Extensive experience in the strategic planning and transportation of products.
- Experience of liaising with forwarders and overseas companies to arrange collections.
- Able to negotiating rates with local contractors and international companies.
- Planning of procurement, production, inventory control, logistics and distribution.

## **Management**

- Possessing creative problem-solving and analytic skills.
- Proven ability to ensure that products are delivered in a good state and on time.
- Willingness to work unusual hours.
- Highly effective motivator with strong written and spoken communication skills.
- An ability to handle the pressures arising from having to meet deadlines and targets.
- Able to evaluate complex situations and find solutions for them.
- Having a passion for delivering excellent customer service in a cost effective way.

#### **KEYCOMPETENCIES AND SKILLS**

- Contract Manufacture.
- Process improvement.
- Project management
- Operational logistics management.
- Supply chain solutions.
- Project based logistics.
- Warehousing & storage.
- Marketing.
- Cost reduction.
- International trade.
- Strategic planning.
- Vendor management.
- UCP-600.
- SAP MM & SD Module.

#### 02. CAREER HISTORY

Head of Supply Chain Management (DGM).
 Noman Group of Industries.
 (1 September 2018 to Till Now).

### Basic Responsibilities.

- 1. Create programs and processes that can improve the supply chain management functions of the company;
- 2. Assure that the corporate goals and objectives of the company will be met, especially those that concern the management of the supply chain;
- 3. Assure that the negotiations and transactions with the different suppliers of the company are properly done and recorded.
- 4. Use the sourcing tools available to assure the cost efficiency of all the procedures that the company undertakes in this field of operations;
- 5. Evaluate the current suppliers of the company and know whether they can still provide the needs of the company for a reasonable price;
- 6. Research on other suppliers, which may give the company requirements in a lower price or in a better quality; and
- 7. Develop lasting professional relationship in the market place to assure that all the supply chain management efforts will be appreciated, seen, and used accordingly.

Head of Supply Chain. (AGM)
 Fakir Apparels ltd.
 (16 April 2017 to 31<sup>st</sup> August 18).

## Basic Responsibilities.

- 1. Sourcing for Trims items Cost of goods purchase cost below 5% out of total cost.
- 2. Sourcing for yarns items Cost of goods purchase cost below 35% out of total cost.
- 3. Sourcing for dyes chemical Cost of goods purchase cost below 10% out of total cost.
- 4. Function in a leadership role, providing coaching, supervision and mentoring for a team of 35 member.
- 5. Responsible for all aspects of commodity management, buyers, product line purchasing, indirect material, supplier quality/development, policy and procedures.
- 6. Developing and implementing company-wide purchasing mentality based on principals recognized as best practices within Knit industry.
- 7. Driving a sense of urgency throughout the team while delivering internal and external commitments in a dynamic competitive environment.
- 8. Aligning Purchasing, Engineering, Manufacturing and Production Planning across all aspects of the business to enhance productivity, quality, capital utilization and profitability.
- 9. Creating and installing standard scorecards metrics for Purchasing, Supplier Quality and Suppliers.
- 10. Challenging Suppliers to be creative and innovative with supply strategies to exceed business segment expectations in quality, delivery, savings and technology needs.

# Dekko Group Head of Procurement.

(Garments & Accessories) 19<sup>th</sup> June 2014 to 13 April 2017.

#### Basic Responsibilities.

- 1. Implement procurement strategy and policies.
- 2. Forecast procurement needs.
- 3. Create and implement KPI's.
- 4. Monitor macro trends in supplier and contract base and implement plans to react.
- 5. Build and develop relationships with key suppliers and customers.
- 6. Lead the procurement group in all phases.
- 7. Identify and develop training opportunities.
- 8. Order materials and services as per negotiated and appropriately approved. Review quotations.
- 9. Prepare purchase requisitions, approve and issues purchase orders in accordance with company policy and negotiated terms and conditions.
- 10. Maintain procurement files.
- 11. Track Purchasing activity and measurements.
- 12. Training purchasing Clerks and Salesmen in the department.
- 13. Discuss defective or unacceptable new goods or services with users, vendors and others to determine cause of problem and take corrective and preventative action.
- 14. Ensure supplier compliance with site and company requirement for safety.
- 15. Manage vendor relationships and assist in building effective partnerships.
- 16. Assist department in developing and implementing purchasing strategies for products.

- 17. Responsible for planning, developing and buying materials, parts, supplies and equipment's in a timely and cost effective way; timely manner while maintaining appropriate quality standards and specifications.
- 18. Liaise with Accounts Payable Department to ensure accurate and timely payment of invoices, as necessary for the business with the supplier.
  - **Gemcon Food & Agricultural Products ltd.**

(MEENA BAZAR) **Deputy Manager S**upply Chain

August 2007 to 18 June 2014.

# **Basic Responsibilities**

- 1. Review of budget for TK 200 Crore, Periodic Procurement Budget for all trading /non-trading items, Controlling the purchase and supply of all procured items & services. (Monthly Volume of TK 17.0 Crore.)
- 2. Negotiating price and terms of products with suppliers.

Year 2011 increase 2% Margin, Worth TK 30 lac.

Year 2012 increase 1% Margin, Worth TK 20 lac.

Year 2013 increase 1.5 % Margin, worth TK 20 lac.

- 3. Managing, developing & improving the purchasing team.
- 4. Establishing terms, pricing, quality requirements, delivery, and contracts.
- 5. Find and execute with potential suppliers for imported /local items.
- 6. Negotiate with supplier to get maximum margin of all Trading/ Non-Trading items.
- 7. Working individually to develop Strategy for procurement planning and marketing as well, adhering to all company policies with particular regard to accounting procedures.
- 8. Working individually to create and execute Promotion (regular monthly, festival, special days, etc).
- 9. Reviewing all contracts/agreements to achieve 'best price/best quality' purchasing.
- 10. Preparing & processing requisitions, purchase orders & invoices for purchases.
- 11. Giving sourcing input to colleagues to aid business planning & development.
- 12. Making recommendations & advising senior management on all purchasing issues.
- 13. Maintaining records of supplier contracts, agreements, goods ordered received.
- 14. Planning logistics and distribution.
- 15. Inventory control of Central warehouse.
- 16. L/C open, imported related issue handles.
- 17. Product management (New own brand invent).
- 18. Managing vendor relationships and building effective supply chain partnerships.

# \* Bashundhara Group.

# **Manager Operation.**

November 2005 to July 2007.

## **Basic Responsibilities**

- 1. Sales and business development.
- 2. Strategic and marketing planning.
- 3. Create promotion and offer planning.
- 4. Brand planning and creative inputs on market Communication.
- 5. Key Account Management/ Retention.

# **❖** Madonna Advertising Ltd.

**Manager Client Service.** 

March 2004 to October 2005

#### **Basic Responsibilities**

- 1. New and existing business development.
- 2. Brand Planning.
- 3. Strategic route development and media planning.

# 04. Education

**!** International Trade & Business.

Manufacture & Global Supply Chain Management.

Short course (29<sup>th</sup> January 17-13<sup>th</sup> February 17)

**Federation University of Australia.** 

**Master of International Trade & Business.** 

University of Dhaka.

Result-3.25 out of 4.

(2016-2018).

Post Graduate Diploma

Supply Chain Management.

ISCEA-(USA).

Result-A.

Year of Passing-2015(April)

**❖** M.B.A Marketing & Finance

Atish Dipankar University of Science & Technology.

Result- 3.25 out of 4.

Year of Passing:-2009.

**❖** B.S.S (Pass)

**National University** 

Result: 2<sup>nd</sup> Division

Year of Passing: 2003.

#### ♦ H.S.C

B.A.F Shahin College (Chittagong). Result- 2<sup>nd</sup> Division.

Passing Year- 1996.

#### ❖ S.S.C

T.S.P Complex Secondary School (Chittagong) Result- 1<sup>st</sup> Division (Science).

Passing Year- 1994.

.

## 05. Training

- Took training on Managerial Skill Development training organized by BIDDHI
- Took training on Custom Procedure for Import & Export organized by BD JOBS.
- Took training on **Supply Chain Management** organized by **DCCI**.
- Took training on Global Supply Chain Management from BD JOBS.
- Took training on **Corporate Communication and professional skill** development by Prothom Alo Jobs com and **HR KITS**.
- Took Training on Leadership and People Management from HR KITS.

#### 06. Interests & Hobbies

Playing Cricket & Football

Listening Music & Reading Books during the leisure

Browsing & chatting to get updated knowledge on New Global Issues.

## 07. Personal Information

Father's Name : Md. Abdul Mannan Khan

Mother's Name : Mrs. Feroza Begum

Present Address : House- Showpno Bastob 38/B, Road-02,

Chandmia Housing, Mohammadpur, Dhaka

Permanent Address : Kazi Vila, kalusha road,

Bangla bazar, Barisal.

Date of Birth : 28 April 1979.

Marital Status : Married. Religion : Islam

Nationality : Bangladeshi (by birth)

Contact No. : 01817086095.

# 08. Reference

Md. Kamruzzaman
 General Manager.
 HR & Admin.
 Fakir Apparels ltd.
 Narayanganj
 Mobile No-01715750440.

Sayed Akhter Jamal.
 Director.
 Dekko Accessories Ltd.
 Dhanmondi, Dhaka.
 Mobile No-.01711547833.